喂
Hello.
你好
Hello?
帕特裏克 喂 是你嗎
Patrick. Hello, Patrick, is that you?
尼古拉斯
Nicholas?
帕特裏克 不瞞你說我有個壞消息
Patrick, I'm afraid I have rather bad news.
你在聽嗎
Hello?
喂 帕特裏克 能聽到嗎
Hello, Patrick, can you hear me
我在紐約
I'm in New York.
聲音好像有點延遲
There appears to be a delay.
-你能聽到嗎  -能
- Can you hear me? - Yes.
-是關於你父親的  -我能聽到
- It concerns your father. - I can hear you.
我在呢
I'm here.
你父親前晚去世了 在酒店房間裏
Your father died the night before last, in his hotel room.
這打擊來得太突然了
It must come as an awful shock to you.
可能吧 嗯
Something like that, yes.
不用說你也知道我的感覺
I hardly need to tell you how I feel.
我很崇敬你父親 大家都喜歡他
I adored your father. Everybody liked him.
雖然他有時不好相處
I know he wasn't always the easiest of men.
你在聽嗎 帕特裏克
Are you there, Patrick?
我在 他現在在哪兒
Yes, I'm here. Where is he now?
大衛嗎
David?
他在弗蘭克·E·麥克唐納那兒 麥迪遜的殯儀館
He's at Frank E. Macdonalds, the funeral people on Madison.
大家都去那兒
Everyone goes there.
"寧缺毋濫" 你父親肯定會這麼說
"Only the best or go without," as your father would have said.
如果你想見他 帶回骨灰...
If you want to see him and collect the ashes...
-你嗑藥了嗎  -不 現在沒
- Do you have much on? - Not at this exact moment, no.
那我們得見一面
Then we must meet up.
就在鑰匙俱樂部見吧 喬治·沃特福德也在
Why don't we meet at the Key Club? George Watford's here.
為你父親非凡的一生舉杯
We'll raise a glass to your father's extraordinary life.
還有
Well, until then,
我很遺憾告訴你這麼難過的消息
I'm sorry to be the bearer of such sad tidings.
嗯 真是... 沉重的打擊
Yes, it's...a great blow.
再見
Goodbye.
老混蛋終於死了
Old bastard's only gone and died.
他怎麼死的
How did he die?
忘記問了 我都高興死了
I forgot to ask, I was too dizzy with glee.
不好意思 我是說難過瘋了
I'm sorry, I mean, dazed with grief.
能不能... 別弄我頭髮
I wonder... could you please stop fiddling with my hair?
我得喝點酒 好好喝一杯
I need a drink, a serious drink.
我們慶祝一下
Let's celebrate.
我們可以出去喝一杯
We could go out for a glass of wine.
或者... 你大概不感興趣
Or... you're probably not interested,
但我們被邀請
but we have been invited
跟格利高裏和麗貝卡共進晚餐
to Gregory and Rebecca's for dinner.
"痛苦是在別人吃飯時產生的"
"Suffering's what takes place while other people are eating."
這是誰說的
Who said that?
抱歉 我現在有點混亂
I'm sorry. I'm feeling a bit mad at the moment.
這是段複雜的關係
It was a complicated relationship.
有很多事要考慮
There's a lot to think about.
是 我覺得海洛因也幫不上什麼忙
Yes, I'm not sure the heroin's helping either.
你覺得這樣好嗎
Do you think that was a good idea?
當然不好
Of course it wasn't a good idea!
我只想說
I merely meant that perhaps
這或許是你改變的好時機
this might be a good time to make a change.
重新開始
Start afresh!
在你讓我及時行樂前 我最好先走
I'd better leave before you tell me to seize the fucking day.
他已經死了
Do you think, now he's dead,
你能別再那麼像他嗎
that you could be a little less like him?
不行 我得把他那份也發揮好
Unlikely. I'll merely have to do the work of two.
黛比 對不起 我不擅長陪伴別人
Debbie, I'm sorry, I'm not fit for human company.
別走 留下來
Don't go. Stay.
-回床上來  -不行
- Come back to bed. - I can't.
話說 我聽人說過
You know, I heard it said somewhere
其實悲傷能刺激性慾
that grief was meant to be an aphrodisiac.
你感覺是這樣嗎
Do you think that might be true?
哼 想得美
Ha! You wish.
你媽媽怎麼樣
How's your mother taking it?
她在乍得的救助兒童會工作
She's working with Save The Children in Chad.
消息還沒傳到她那兒
No-one can break the news.
-永遠在為他人著想  -沒錯
- Always thinking of others. - Indeed.
-那是什麼  -鎮定劑
- What's that? - Valium.
這才像話
That's more like it.
對了 我想戒毒了
By the way, I think I'm going to give up drugs.
你覺得我做不到
You don't think I can.
-我有點懷疑  -我之前戒過
- I'm a little skeptical. - I've done it before.
對啊 這次有什麼區別嗎
Exactly! What's so different this time?
你根本不是會戒毒的那種人 你太愛它了
You're hardly the Rehab-type and besides, you like it too much.
除非跌落谷底 癮君子是不會戒毒的
Addicts don't give up until they hit rock bottom,
而你永遠不會
and you never will.
-你太講究了  -不 你錯了
- You're too upholstered. - Well, you're wrong.
我這次會成功的
I'm gonna get it right this time.
好吧 加油 帕特裏克
Well, good for you, Patrick!
至少要戒掉可卡因和海洛因
Cocaine and heroin at least.
想要會跑 得先會走
Don't want to run before I can walk.
說起來 你還有鎮定劑嗎
To which end, have you got any more Valium?
-為了幫我戒毒  -抱歉 最後一支
- Help me wean myself off. - Sorry, last one.
我沒別的意思 但你是不是要暴富了
Please don't take this the wrong way, does this mean you're now fantastically rich?
不 我媽媽才是繼承人
No, my mummy's the one with all the money,
而且她非常健康
and she's very healthy.
"太陽升起 一切如常" [語出塞繆爾·貝克特 "墨菲"]
"And the sun shone, having no alternative."
好 該及時行樂了
Well, it's time to seize the fucking day!
再見
Goodbye.
你也再見
And goodbye.
再見了 海洛因 我的老朋友
And goodbye, heroin, my old friend.
大家把戒毒想得太複雜了
People make far too big a deal about getting clean.
不過話說回來... 坐飛機會很緊張的
On the other hand... air travel can be very stressful.
那祝你好運
Well, good luck.
別在大街上出醜
Don't score off the streets.
我根本就不會出醜
I'm not going to score off anywhere.
說真的 強尼 你得隨心所欲
Seriously, Johnny. You must do whatever you want,
我要是想掌控自己的人生 得從現在開始
but if I'm to take control of my life, it has to be now.
這對於我
This is one of the most important things
是非常重要的事
to have happened to me
這次我一定要成功
and I want to get it absolutely right.
真羨慕你的決心
I wish I had your determination.
謝謝你送我
Thank you for the lift.
和其他時候一樣
As in so many other occasions,
沒有你 我做不到
I wouldn't have made it without you.
我的榮幸 兩天後再見 你就是全新的人
It's a pleasure. I'll see you back here in two days' time, a new man.
脫胎換骨
An entirely new man.
來自倫敦希思羅機場的
Will all passengers recently arrived
各位旅客
from London Heathrow,
請到行李領取處...
please make your way to the baggage claim...
"死了 那麼久
"Dead, long dead.
那麼久 我的心已化為塵土"[語出丁尼生 "莫德"]
Long dead! And my heart is a handful of dust."
還有... 別的... 什麼
And... something... something else.
我的天 振作一點
Oh, for Christ's sake, cheer up.
想點高興的
Think happy thoughts.
記住你為什麼來
Remember why you're here.
你是來給你爹收屍的
You're here to collect your father's corpse!
鎮定劑失效了 感覺有點焦躁
Valium's wearing off, feeling just a little twitchy now.
鎮靜... 克制
Hold on. Just... hold on.
噁心 焦慮 皮膚裏像有蟲子爬
Queasy, nervous, maggots under the skin,
胃裏像有溺水的小貓
litter of drowning kittens in my stomach.
媽的
Fuck off!
你能換條路嗎
Can you take another route?
我真的 真的得趕緊到酒店
I really, really need to get to my hotel.
給
Here.
梅爾羅斯先生 很高興再次見面
Mr. Melrose! Good to see you again.
您的常住套房已經準備好了
Your usual suite is ready.
還有一條留言
And a message for you.
真是意味深長
Always eloquent.
麻煩您送一瓶威士忌上來
Could you please send up a bottle of whiskey
還有很多冰塊...
and a very great deal of ice...
沒問題
Of course.
這是電梯
This is the lift.
這是按鈕 您住33樓
Here are the buttons. You're on the 33rd floor.
33!
-我的天 怎麼克制啊  -您說什麼 先生
- Christ, talk about temptation. - Beg pardon, sir?
沒什麼 我在自言自語
Oh, nothing. Just talking to myself.
這是走廊
This is the hallway.
這是您的房間 3318
Here is your room. 3318.
這是您的鑰匙
This is your key.
開了
It works!
開始了 你知道流程
Here we go, you know the drill.
又一次在國外酒店戒毒
Another withdrawal in a foreign hotel room.
浴室的燈
Bathroom light.
這是您的電視 在這兒打開
Here's your TV, turn it on here.
您可以這樣切換頻道
And this is how you change channels.
我知道 我以前用過電視
Yes, I have used a television before.
恐懼 抽筋 自殺的念頭...
Paranoia, cramps, suicidal thoughts...
謝謝
Thank you.
至少 這是最後一次了
Still, at least it's the last time.
或是最後幾次中的一次
Or among the last times.
這次不行 這次不一樣
Not this time. This time it's different.
不當囚犯 要像火焰噴射器一樣專注
No prisoners. Concentration like a flame-thrower.
新的一天 新的開始
New day, new beginning.
關鍵在於不想它
The trick is not to think about it.
怎麼可能不想它呢
How can you not think about it?
就像房間著火的時候
It's like not wanting to get out of a wheelchair
不想離開輪椅
when the room's on fire.
我的天
Oh, God.
想要城裏最好的海洛因
For the best heroin in town,
打給皮埃爾 555-1726
simple call Pierre, 555-1726.
皮埃爾 555-1726
That's Pierre, 555-1726.
不要想它
Don't think about it.
帕特裏克!
Patrick!
怎麼了 管家
Yes, Nanny?
年輕人 你需要去公園散散步
What you need, young man, is a nice walk in the park.
但 不要海洛因
No smack, though!
這我得說清楚
I want to make that absolutely clear!
不 管家 不要海洛因 我發誓
No, Nanny. No smack, I swear.
有安眠酮嗎
Got any Quaaludes?
嗯 我有 萊蒙741 五刀一個
Sure, I got Quaaludes. Lemmon 714s, five dollars each.
我不能指望立馬戒掉一切 對吧
I can hardly be expected to give up everything at once. Can I?
來五個 不 六個 苯丙胺[興奮劑]有嗎
I'll take five, no, six. What about speed?
為啥要買苯丙胺 你瘋了嗎
Why the hell are you buying speed. Are you mad?
我有黑美人[興奮劑] 哥們 正經藥
Yo. I got some Black Beauties, man. They're pharmaceutical.
就是你自己做的唄
Meaning you made them yourself?
-意思是藥很好  -不要買苯丙胺
- Meaning they're good. - Do not buy any speed.
來三個 衝動消費
Give me three. Impulse buy.
-你是英國人吧  -是
- Ooh, you're British, right? - That's right.
穿著大衣不熱嗎
Ain't you hot in that coat?
聽說你們那兒海洛因免費
I hear they give you free heroin there?
-別騷擾他 -嗯 不完全
- Don't bother the man. - Well, not exactly free.
脫了大衣 哥們 你在出汗
Take your coat off, man, you sweating.
來點海洛因嗎 英國佬
Wanna buy some smack, British guy?
我也有可卡因 超棒
I got cocaine too, real good shit.
我說了別煩他
I said don't bother him.
我相信你 但我已經戒了
I don't doubt it, but I've given that up!
哥們 你得喝點水 哥們
Yo, man, you need some water, man.
我可是專業的
I'm not an amateur.
明天再來啊
Yo, you come back here tomorrow!
有什麼能幫您嗎 先生
Can I help you, sir?
嗯 我是來告別遺體的
Yes, I've come to see the corpse.
抱歉 我能要杯水嗎 我...
Sorry, can I have a glass of water? I...
一大顆藥卡在我的...
I have a large pill stuck in my...
唾液不夠...
Not enough saliva...
好了
Now.
我來領大衛·梅爾羅斯的遺體
I've come to see the corpse of David Melrose.
梅爾羅斯先生在走廊盡頭
You'll find Mr. Melrose at the end of the corridor.
帕特裏克 過來 快來
Patrick! Come here! Right now!
水星 金星 地球 火星...
Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars...
木星 土星 天王星
Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus,
-馬提尼 先生  -啥 不用 謝謝
- Martini, sir. - What? No, thank you.
經典莫吉托呢
Mojito Old-fashioned?
你怎麼認識赫爾曼的
Oh, how did you know Hermann?
真他媽難以置信
I can't fucking believe it!
注意言辭
Whoa, there!
屍體他媽不對
Wrong fucking corpse!
-你確定嗎  -死亡能改變一切
- Oh. Are you sure? - Death transforms us all,
但沒強大到把我父親變成猶太矮子
but it's not so powerful as to turn my father into a small Jew.
再確認一下
Try again.
但樓裏沒有別的聚會啊
But we don't have another party in the building.
我不想參加聚會 我是來見大衛·梅爾羅斯的
I don't want to go to a party, I want to see David Melrose!
-應該在這兒  -謝謝
- This is the correct room. - Thank you.
-麻煩替我道個歉...  -不不不
- And please apologize to... - No, no, no.
您情緒激動是正常的
It's an emotional time.
是 所以我吃了安眠酮
Yes, that's why I took a Quaalude
但好像沒用
but it must have been a dud.
-我很遺憾  -我能之後再來取骨灰嗎
- Oh, I'm sorry to hear that. - Can I pick him up later?
可以的話 我想先離開紐約
I would like to get away from New York if at all possible.
您明天午後方可領走令尊的骨灰
Your father's ashes will be available tomorrow afternoon.
這樣啊 快點不行嗎
I see. No chance of a rush job?
我不打擾你們了
I'll leave you alone with him.
幹點正事
Get this right.
這... 這是我爸嗎
Is it... Is it Dad?
還真是 就是我相見的
It is! It's just what I wanted!
不該這麼說
You shouldn't have!
媽的 老爸 你在棺材裏幹嘛
Fucking hell, Dad. What are you doing in a coffin?
這兒怎麼了
What happened here?
你不想死 對吧
You didn't want to go, did you?
你知道自己要死 沒錯
You knew you were going to die and you were right.
什麼感覺
What did that feel like?
痛苦嗎 憤怒嗎
Pain or rage?
你害怕嗎
Were you scared?
天啊 希望如此
Christ, I hope so.
不 不對
No. No.
不會的 不可能
No, no, no!
操
Fuck.
你真他媽好慘哦 老爸
Aw, you're so fucking sad, Dad, man,
你還想讓我難過
and now you're trying to make me sad too.
沒門
Well, bad luck.
嗨 帕特裏克
Hello, Patrick.
怎麼了
What's up?
你在發抖
You're shaking.
怎麼回事 帕特裏克
What is it, Patrick?
你媽媽呢 想跟她說說嗎
What about your mother? You want to tell your mother?
好 我馬上回來 我保證
Okay, I'll be right back. I promise.
看著很有意思
Well, that looks fun.
抗生素而已
Antibiotics.
-帕特裏克 我很遺憾  -我也是
- Patrick. I am so sorry. - I'm sorry too.
準時是我從父親那遺傳的
Punctuality is one of the smaller vices
小缺陷之一
I've inherited from my father.
你知道我說的不是這個
I think you know that's not what I meant.
-麻煩來杯茶 伯爵紅茶  -好的
- Oh, tea, please, Earl Grey. - Uh-huh.
-能再來一杯嗎  -可以
- And another of these? - Certainly.
對我來說 現在是9點
For me, it's nine o'clock.
對你 永遠都是9點
For you, it's always nine o'clock.
管他呢... 麻煩也給我一杯馬提尼
Oh, what the hell... a martini for me too, please.
-你去過...  -太平間嗎
- So, have you been to... - The mortuary?
去過了 是我見過他最好的狀態了
Yes, yes, the best I've ever seen him.
我不想讓你幻想破滅
Well, I don't wanna disillusion you,
不過他們給你的骨灰
but when they give you the ashes,
只是從爐底
they're really just the communal rakings
-隨便鏟的  -那很好啊
- from the bottom of the oven. - That's good news!
理論上 它們各有所屬
Ideally they'd all belong to someone else.
小時候 父親常帶我去飯店...
When I was young, he used to take us to restaurants...
很多飯店
I say restaurants in the plural,
因為我們每天進出至少三家
because we never stormed in and out of less than three.
我記得有一次 他倒提一瓶干紅
I remember one occasion he held a bottle of claret upside down
酒咕咚咕咚流到地毯上
as the contents gurgle out onto the carpet.
"你們怎敢給我這等污物"
"How dare you bring me this filth?"
現在他在那邊沒法抱怨了
Well, at least he's somewhere he can't complain about.
我還想著他從棺材裏坐起來
I half expected him to sit upright in the coffin
像日落時的吸血鬼
like a vampire at sunset.
"這也算棺材 這裏的服務簡直不能忍"
"Call this a coffin? The service here is intolerable!"
別說 他們的服務真的不行
Mind you, the service was intolerable.
給我指到別人那兒去了
They sent me to the wrong corpse.
-別的屍體  -對
- The wrong corpse? - Yes.
真諷刺 父親屍骨難尋
Ironic that my father's remains were so hard to find,
我身上卻滿是他的影子
when I have no trouble discovering them in myself.
很高興見到你 安妮
It's good to see you, Anne.
我真得見個熟人緩緩
I did need to see a friendly face.
確實...他是個複雜的人
Well...he was a complicated man.
因此我今天才...
Which is why I was...
急切地想跟你談談
so keen to talk to you today.
-安眠酮總算起效了  -帕特裏克 你還好嗎
- Here come the Quaaludes. - Patrick, are you okay?
有一點... 時差
Jet-lag... kicking in.
-要躺一下嗎  -不用這麼誇張
- You wanna go lie down? - No, let's not exaggerate.
就稍微有點困
Just a little sleepy.
抗生素
The antibiotics.
不好意思了
Excuse me.
梅爾羅斯先生
Mr. Melrose!
您還好嗎
All good?
時差很嚴重
Very jet-lagged.
操
Oh, fuck.
這就行了
That'll fool 'em!
我的天
Oh, good God.
-幹嘛去了你  -洗了把臉
- What happened to you in there? - I splashed my face with water!
-什麼水  -非常提神的水
- What kind of water? - Very refreshing water.
帕特裏克 請你坐好 你讓我有點緊張
Patrick, please sit down, you're making me nervous.
是 人們常這麼說
Yes, yes, people say this.
帕特裏克 我真心想向你道歉
Patrick, I really wanted to apologize.
我看到你在樓梯上時...
When I found you on the stairs...
-不 別提這事  -我答應了把你媽媽找來
- No, no, not this. - I promised I'd get your mother.
別說了 聽不見 聽不見
Retreat, escape, eject, eject!
我保證 我全都忘了
And I promise you, I've forgotten all about it.
-服務員呢  -你當時很難過
- Where is our waiter? - You seemed in distress.
你總是這樣 你媽媽也是
You always did. Your mother too.
那棟房子有那種氛圍
There was such an atmosphere in that house.
我本該幫你的
And I should've done more.
不好意思 我... 真得走了
I'm sorry. I... I really have to go.
什麼 我們才...
What? We've barely...
我5點前要到律師那兒 簽些文件
I have to be at the solicitor's by five. Papers to sign.
-真的嗎 我們才剛剛...  -真煩人對吧
- Really? But we've only just... - Maddening, isn't it?
但你知道 得走程序
But, you know, bureaucracy.
我也沒辦法 所以...
There's only so much I can do, so...
我很感激 你一直待我不薄
Look, I am grateful. You were always very kind to me,
從小就是 非常感謝你
ever since I was young and I'm very grateful.
可我... 現在... 真得走了
But I... I really... I really must be going now.
走啦 拜
Bye. Bye!
我們已攻下紅海[語出"阿拉伯的勞倫斯" 第35屆奧斯卡最佳影片]
We've taken Aqaba!
先生
Sir?
再來杯超級提神的馬提尼
I'll have another of your very refreshing martinis,
還有韃靼三文魚 韃靼牛肉
and some salmon tartare followed by steak tartare
韃靼 韃靼 要辣 多加辣
tartare-tartare, spicy, very spicy.
再給我一份酒水單
And your wine list.
好孩子 帕特裏克 吃點好東西
Good boy, Patrick. Get something solid inside you.
-閉嘴 管家  -有人... 和您共同進餐嗎
- Do be quiet, Nanny. - Will... someone be joining you?
老天啊 我希望沒有
Fucking hell, I hope not!
寧缺毋濫
Only the best or go without!
看到沒 還是管用
You see? That still works.
一切都在掌控之中
Everything is under control.
很好 謝謝你
Very good, thank you.
但這不是海洛因
But it's not heroin.
大部分人 要戒掉海洛因 靠興奮劑抽嗨
Most people, withdrawing from heroin, high on speed,
或被安眠酮和時差搞暈時
cudgeled by Quaaludes and jet-lag
可能會抗拒食物 但我不是
might balk at the idea of food, but not I.
我進食不是因為餓 而是因為激情
I eat not from greed but from passion!
閉嘴 可以嗎
Do shut up, will you?
-不是說你... 是其他人  -先生想吃甜點嗎[care for也有照顧之意]
- Not you...someone else. - Would sir care for a dessert?
照顧它 怎麼照顧甜點
Care for it? How do you care for dessert?
餵它嗎 週日去看它嗎
Feed it? Visit it on Sundays?
我要一份焦糖奶油和一瓶勃艮第白蘭地
I'll have a creme brûlee and a Marc de Bourgogne.
但這依然不是海洛因 對吧
But it's still not heroin, is it?
海洛因是騎兵 是缺失的椅子腿
Heroin's the cavalry, the missing chair leg.
海洛因是愛 只要打給555-1726...
Heroin is love. Simply call 555-1726...
閉嘴
Shut up!
-您一切都好嗎 先生  -你問了好幾遍
- Everything okay, sir? - You keep asking that.
怎麼可能一切都好  要求太高了
But how can everything be okay? It's simply too much to hope.
因為 很多人在抱怨
Because, there have been some complaints.
我腦子裏的聲音別人也聽得到嗎
You mean the voices aren't just in my head?
該死 或許我該去拿...
Fuck! Perhaps I ought to get the...
請問你能借我25美分
I don't suppose I could trouble you for a quarter
去打電話嗎
for the telephone?
不如這樣吧
Here's the deal.
如果他接了 就吸夠睡覺的海洛因
If he answers, score just enough smack to sleep
再為明早留一點
and a little for the morning.
就這樣 如果他不接 就不吸海洛因了
That's all. And if he doesn't answer, no smack at all.
交給命運了
Leave it to fate.
好主意
Good idea.
555-1726
555-1726.
我是皮埃爾
This is Pierre.
我現在不能接電話...
I can't come to the phone, right now...
去你的 命運 操 操
Fuck you, fate! Fuck, fuck.
干他媽的命運 操
Fuck, fucking fate, fuck, fuck!
天啊
Oh, God.
好了 先生 我們到了
Okay, man, we're here!
-這不是個好地方  -我全靠這個活
- This is a bad place, y'know. - That's what I'm relying on.
在這兒等我
Just wait here for me.
瘋子 我才不等呢
Crazy man. I'm not waiting here!
操
Oh, fuck.
你想要什麼 找什麼呢
What you want, man? What are you looking for?
-海洛因  -媽的
- Smack. - Shit.
-你是警察嗎  -當然不是
- You a policeman? - Certainly not.
我是英國人 能帶我去洛蕾塔那兒嗎
I'm an Englishman. Can you take me to Loretta's?
當然 我可以帶你去洛蕾塔那兒
Sure, I can take you to Loretta's.
這邊
This way.
你想要 是嗎
You want it, don't cha?
別捅他 別捅他
Don't stick him! Don't stick him!
Don't stick him! Don't stick him! Don't stick him!
別捅他
Don't stick him!
他... 他是我朋友
He... He's my man.
-你好 希利  -我不知道你認識希利
- Hello, Chilly! - I didn't know you knew Chilly.
是啊 這世界真小
Yeah, well, it's a small world.
你真要捅我嗎
Were you really going to stab me?
我當然要捅你
Sure I was gonna stab you!
看
Here.
我叫馬克
My name's Mark.
謝謝你不捅我 馬克
Well, thank you, Mark, for not stabbing me!
你去哪兒了 帕特裏克
Where you been, Patrick?
到處逛逛
Oh, here and there.
-你能帶我去洛蕾塔那兒嗎  -嗯...
- Can you take me to Loretta's? - Yeah, it's...
不 這邊
No. It's this way.
-你看起來很好  -我感覺不好
- Oh, man, you look good! - I don't feel good.
-誰  -希利·威利
- Who is it? - Chilly Willy.
-你要多少  -50
- How much you want? - 50.
60.
威利夫人怎麼樣 希利 她還好嗎
So how's Mrs. Willy, Chilly? She well?
給你
Here.
寶貝 寶貝
Hey, baby, baby, baby.
看我得到了什麼
Look what I got!
這屋子變了 不一樣了
You've done something to the room. It's different.
-怎麼回事  -著火了
- What's different? - It got on fire.
我就知道
I knew there was something.
希利說你可能有新注射器
Chilly says you might have a new syringe.
不是全新的 但我煮過了
Well, it ain't exactly new, but I've boiled it and everything.
很鈍嗎
Is it very blunt?
天啊 那不是注射器 是自行車氣筒
Christ, that's not a syringe, it's a bicycle pump.
好吧 好吧
No, alright, alright.
-多少錢  -兩袋
- How much? - Two bags.
能借用你的衛生間嗎
Could I possibly use your bathroom?
去吧
Come on.
天啊...
Oh, God...
該死的
Shit. Fuck!
媽的
For fuck's sake!
希利 能建議你換個新燈泡嗎
Might I suggest, Chilly, that you invest in a new light bulb?
根本沒用 我沒扎到血管
Hardly worth the effort, I missed the vein.
你...
You...
應該用手電筒的
should have used the flashlight.
謝謝你告訴我 我要好點的東西 希利
Well, thanks for telling me! I need better works, Chilly.
希利 希利
Chilly. Chilly!
操
Oh, fuck.
好吧 我們做好做這事
Right, then, let's do this properly.
寧缺毋濫
Only the best or go without.
哥倫比亞可卡因 然後中國白粉
Columbian cocaine and then China White.
拜託 皮埃爾 接電話
Come on, Pierre. Just be there, will you?
555-1726
555-1726.
-喂  -皮埃爾 真的是你嗎
- Âllo - Pierre,Is that really you?
-你是誰  -倫敦的帕特裏克
- Who is this? - Patrick from London.
我... 我睡不著
I'm...having trouble sleeping.
二十分鐘
20 minutes.
-你好嗎  -真是場噩夢
- Ça va? - It's a nightmare out there.
那... 他怎麼樣
So...what was he like?
我父親嗎
My father?
他最好了 正人君子一個
He was a kitten. A prince among men.
他有藝術家的手 本可以成為首相的
He had very artistic hands. Could have been Prime Minister.
他是個政治家嗎
He was a politician?
不 不 開個玩笑
No, no, no, it was sort of a joke.
在他看來
In his world, it was better
要是能當首相更好
if you could have been Prime Minister,
或者... 外科醫生 鋼琴演奏家
or a...surgeon, or a concert pianist.
嘗試後 有所成就
To have tried and actually achieved something
表現出庸俗的野心
would have shown vulgar ambition.
你為他的死難過嗎
Tu regrettes qu'il soit mort?
我為他活過而難過
I regret he lived.
但沒有他...
Mais sans lui...
就沒有你
you wouldn't exist.
人對這些事不能太自我
One mustn't be too egotistical about these things.
現在是可卡因時間
Now for the cocaine.
我一直想戒了它
I had been trying to give this up.
-現在...  -天哪
- Now... - Oh, God.
注射... 海洛因
take...the heroin!
天哪
Oh, God. Oh, God.
我真在萊班酒店吃過飯...
Truly I have dined in Les Bains...
我還在... 蘇丹喀土穆吃過飯
I've also dined in... Khartoum.
當時 兇狠的年輕木乃伊
When the ferocious young mummy
給了我一盤人肉
offered me a dish of human flesh,
我不允許假正經
I did not allow prudishness
阻止我要第三盤的衝動
to prevent me from requesting a third portion.
其實 我沒有... 人肉
Indeed, I did not... Human flesh?
我問你 接下來呢
I ask you, what next?
你一直都是個怪男孩
You always were a strange boy.
今晚的特色菜包括 免費沙拉
Tonight's special includes a free salad
哥倫比亞可卡因
Columbian cocaine,
和中國白海洛因...
nestling on a bed of wild baby Chinese White Heroin...
我告訴你貴族和他們的骯髒手段
I tell you about the aristocracy and their filthy ways.
別 別 別想它 什麼骯髒手段
Don't, don't, don't think about it. What filthy ways?
哪個管家出了學校都不會說的
You won't find Nanny telling tales out of school.
我會守口如瓶 但我的好故事可多了
My lips are sealed. But, oh, the stories I could tell you!
拜託 停下來
Please, please, please make it stop!
現在 我要你感受安靜
Now, I want you to listen to the silence.
感受到了嗎 融入這份寧靜
Can you hear it? Become part of the silence.
好 現在我要你想像一座寶塔
Good. Now I want you to visualize a pagoda.
看到了嗎 漂亮吧
Can you see it? Beautiful isn't it?
對 羅恩 很漂亮
Yes, yes, Ron, it is. It's beautiful.
現在 我要你走進去 帕特裏克
Now I want you to step into it, Patrick.
裏面有東西嗎
Is there something in there?
有 帕特裏克 你媽媽和爸爸
Yes, Patrick. Your mum and dad.
媽媽和爸爸
Mum and Dad?
我要你走向媽媽
I want you to go up to your mother
我想讓你跟她說 "我愛你 媽咪"
I want you to say to her "I love you, Mummy."
媽媽 我真的愛你
Mum, I really love you.
很好 現在擁抱她
That's good, now embrace her.
感覺不錯吧
Feels good, doesn't it?
對 感覺很好
Yes, it feels so good.
現在 我要你走向爸爸
Now I want you to go up to your father
跟他說 "而你 我不能原諒"
and say "You, on the other hand, I cannot forgive."
而你 我不能原諒 滾開
You, on the other hand, I cannot forgive. Fuck off.
很好 現在 用左輪手槍射他的腦袋
Good, now take a revolver and shoot his fucking brains out.
呯 呯 呯 呯
Bang, bang, bang, bang!
要是你敢告訴你媽媽
If you ever tell your mother,
或者其他人 今天的事...
or anyone else, about today...
我就把你折成兩截
I will snap you in two!
滾開 所有人
Fuck off, all of you!
注射海洛因 現在
So take the heroin, then. Take it now.
喂 喂 帕特裏克
Hello. Hello Patrick
媽媽
Mother?
聽得到嗎
Can you hear me?
帕特裏克 我聽說了
Patrick, I heard the news.
-我不知道該說什麼  -媽媽
- I don't know what to say. -  Mother?
-喂  -喂 是我
- Hello? - Hello! It's me!
-靠  -你聽起來很困
- Fuck! - You sound sleepy.
你在睡覺嗎
Are you sleeping?
我把你吵醒了嗎
Have I woken you up?
很抱歉 非常 非常對不起
Oh. I am so sorry, sorry, sorry
現在是早上5點半
It's five-thirty in the morning.
我以為你有時差 會在房間裏走走
Well, I thought with the jet-lag you'd be pacing the room.
你在酒店嗎
Are you at the hotel?
鑒於你打的是酒店的電話...
Given that you've phoned me here...
我只想說 我一整晚都在擔心你
I merely meant, I have been up all night worrying about you
想知道你怎麼樣
and wanted to know how you are.
你想問我有沒有嗑藥
You mean have I taken any drugs?
不 不僅是這個
No. Not just that.
怎麼了 你嗑了嗎
Why? Have you?
我一整晚都在注射可卡因和海洛因
Well, I've been shooting cocaine and heroin all night.
-這算嗎  -好辦法啊
- Does that count. - Well, such a good idea.
以後 我們能不能達成一致 不 這不是好辦法
In the future, can we agree that, no, it is not a good idea?
我以為... 我真的以為你能改變
I thought... I really thought you'd be able to make a change.
我也以為 但顯然不是這樣
Yeah. Me, too. But apparently that's not an option.
你不應該一個人的
You shouldn't be alone.
我安排了你跟別人共進晚餐
I have arranged for you to have dinner with someone.
不 黛比 這不是你的晚宴
No, Debbie, this is not one of your dinner parties.
我現在情緒激動
It's a very emotional time.
我的狀態不適合見任何人
I'm not in a fit state to see anyone.
你要跟關心你的人在一起
You need to be with people who care about you
我跟瑪麗安約好了
and I've already fixed it with Marianne.
-瑪麗安  -我大學的老朋友
- Marianne? - My old university friend.
你在她的廁所暈過去了 他們得把門拆了
You passed out in her loo. They had to take the doors off.
-記得嗎  -那個瑪麗安啊
- Remember? - Oh, that Marianne.
她想見你 7點半之後都可以
She'd love to see you. Any time after seven-thirty.
我給你傳真地址
I've faxed you the address.
我得跟我爸的狐朋狗友喝酒 不過...
I've got drinks with my father's awful friends but...
看看晚點能不能去
I'll see whether I'm up to it later.
記住 我... 我真的愛你
Remember, I... I do love you.
帕特裏克
Patrick?
瑪麗安 瑪麗安 瑪麗安
Marianne, Marianne, Marianne.
帕特裏克 很高興見到你
Hi, Patrick. It's so nice to see you.
跟懂的人聊天真是舒服
It's so wonderful to talk to someone who understands.
沒有冰塊 忍不了
No ice! This is intolerable!
全都不對勁 一切都很糟糕
Everything's wrong, everything's hopelessly fucked up!
冰塊 我要很多冰塊 拜託
Ice! Must have more of your delicious ice, por favor!
3318房
Room 3318.
靠
Shit.
它依然非常鋒利
And still remain razor-sharp.
而且 這把刀永遠不會鈍
What's more, it's a knife that will last forever.
這樣的好刀 您願意出多少錢呢
How much would you pay for a knife like this?
在您作答前 聽好了...
Before you answer, listen...
我們還附贈配套叉子 給您極佳的用餐體驗
It comes with a matching fork to make carving a pleasure.
別急 贈品不止一件
Wait, there's much, much more.
您還將擁有這套六合一廚具
We also want you to have this six-in-one kitchen tool.
它能給胡蘿蔔和土豆去皮
It peels and slivers carrots, peels potatoes
還能切出薄薄的土豆片
and slices paper-thin potato chips.
-這套超棒的...  -這不是我的手
- This amazing... - These aren't my arms.
...還能處理奶酪 做出漂亮的裝飾蔬菜
...cheese and makes beautiful decorative vegetables.
你同意嗎
Do you agree?
準備好
Pip, pip! Be prepared.
-帕特裏克 真準時  -喬治
- Ah, Patrick. Bang on time. - George!
跟你爸一樣 他非常為你驕傲
Just like your father. He was very, very proud of you.
-你一定知道吧  -小伙子你好
- I expect you know that. - Hello, little man.
請節哀順變 你很難過吧
I'm sorry for your loss. You must be feeling ghastly.
你眼睛怎麼了 感情問題嗎
What happened to your eye? Girl trouble?
既然我負責引導你的道德...
Now that I'm responsible for your moral guidance...
不 不是的 我在飛機上撞的
No, nothing like that. I just picked something up on the plane.
挺適合你 很瀟灑
It suits you. Very raffish.
-這地方很適合你  -沒錯
- You'll fit right in here. - Yes!
你肯定會喜歡的
I think you'll find this place amusing.
你爸就很喜歡
I mean, your father did.
英國再也找不到的東西 這兒都有
It has all the things that you can't find in England anymore.
你喝摻湯雞尾酒了嗎
Have you had a Bullshot?
-沒有  -服務員
- No. - Waiter, waiter!
-您好  -三杯摻湯雞尾酒  -馬上
- Yes, sir? - Three Bullshots, please. - Right away.
我邀請了巴蘭坦·摩根
I've invited Ballantine Morgan,
不過他這人無聊得很
though I suspect he's the most frightful bore.
他家有銀行 至少我這麼覺得
His family own a bank. At least I think they do.
我向他求證過 可他的回答
I've asked the question, but it's so hard
真他媽聽不下去
to listen to his fucking answers.
來吧 大夥兒都在
Here we are. The gang's all here.
-這位是巴蘭坦·摩根  -節哀順變
- This is Ballantine Morgan. - So sorry about your father.
我不認識他本人 但聽喬治說
I didn't know him personally but from what George tells me,
他真是位英國紳士
he was a great English gentleman!
喬治 你都跟他說了什麼
George! What have you been telling him?
你父親是多麼了不起
Only what an exceptional man your father was.
反正我沒見過和他一樣的人
Well, I never met anybody quite like him.
他從不妥協
He refused to compromise!
"寧缺毋濫"
"Nothing but the best, or go without!"
我很贊成
I quite agree!
"不道歉 不解釋" 這句也很經典
"Never apologize, never explain". That was another one.
"仔細觀察 別輕信人"
"Observe everything, Trust no-one."
-都很睿智  -"少折騰 都沒用"
- All very wise. - "Never try, effort's vulgar."
"18世紀才是好時光"
"Things were better in the 18th century."
對了 還有"女人算什麼 特別是你媽"
Oh, and, "Despise all women, but your mother most of all."
摻湯雞尾酒來了
Here are our Bullshots!
牛肉湯加伏特加 需要慢慢品味
Beef consomme and vodka; something of an acquired taste.
品到了 再來一杯
I've acquired it! Another, please.
他父親是位出色的鋼琴家
His father was a very impressive pianist.
-彈的都是別人的  -交際也很強
- If you like pastiche. - And in conversation too.
看情況 有些人不喜歡毫無禮貌的交談
That depends. Some people don't like uninterrupted rudeness,
-我是這麼聽說的  -誰說的啊
- or so I'm told. - Who are these people?
沒錯 有一次我勸他說話別那麼沖
It's true, I did once ask him to stop being so argumentative.
-他怎麼回答  -叫我滾蛋
- What did he say? - Told me to bugger off!
真是群忠實的老狗
What a lot of faithful gun dogs.
-你說什麼  -看
- Sorry? - There.
你喜歡打獵嗎 帕特裏克
Are you interested in hunting, Patrick?
天吶 開始了
Oh, Christ, here we go.
有個故事他可能想聽
I thought he might be interested in a story.
你就沒想過 有人不想聽嗎
The thought you never have is that someone might not be interested.
當時我正要開槍殺一隻坦噶尼喀山羊
I'd shot this Tanganyikan mountain goat,
種群裏的最後一隻公羊
the last male of its species,
沒錯 那是個苦樂參半的瞬間
which, of course, was a rather bittersweet moment.
對山羊來說 當然
For the goat, certainly.
我有個打獵的故事 巴蘭坦 關於我爸的
I've got a hunting story for you, Ballantine, from my father.
-尼古拉斯 你知道的  -冷靜點 帕特裏克
- Nicholas, you know the one. - Steady on, Patrick.
-夠了  -我爸當過騎兵軍官
- Enough now. - Father was a cavalry officer
在20年代駐紮印度
stationed in India in the 1920s,
他喜歡獵豬 帶著長矛穿過草叢
and he used to go pig-sticking, galloping through the high grass
尋找野豬
with a lance, hunting wild boar.
那些野豬很兇猛 能撞倒馬匹
Very dangerous, these wild boar. They could take down a horse,
把人頂死 但也很刺激
and gore a rider to death, but thrilling too.
總之 那次狩獵唯一的遺憾...
Anyway, the only blemish on this particular trip...
我聽這故事時好像才8歲吧
I think I heard this story when I was, what, eight?
...是有個獵人被一隻野狗咬了
...was that one of the hunting party was bitten by a wild dog
狂犬病發作
and developed the symptoms of rabies.
最近的醫院要三天的路程
Three days from the nearest hospital and this hunting party
所以這群將軍和大人決定
of judges and generals decided to truss up
把這位口吐白沫的朋友綁起來
their foaming, thrashing friend in a net
用一張網吊在半空中
and hoist him off the ground.
晚飯開始了...
Dinner was served...
桌上放著燈 銀光閃閃
Lanterns down the table, gleam of silver,
僕人們訓練有素
well-trained servants.
可在尖叫聲中 我們誰都吃不下飯
But none of us could quite enjoy dinner with all that screaming.
於是我離開餐桌
So I got up from the table,
拿上手槍 走向那個發瘋的人
fetched my pistol, went over to the rabid man
給了他腦袋一槍
and shot him in the head.
這是最仁慈的做法
Much the kindest thing to do.
到最後
Everyone agreed.
人人都接受
Eventually.
我想就是那時
And that, I think,
我與藥物結下了不解之緣
was the beginning of my love affair with medicine.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你應該進隔間
You might have used the stall!
好主意
Good idea.
天啊 爸爸
Oh, Christ. Dad.
我得去拿骨灰 媽的
I've got to pick up Dad. Fuck.
借過
Excuse me.
你好 嘿
Hello. Hello?
拜託 我爸還在裏面
Please. You have my father!
-我們已經打烊了  -不行
- I'm afraid we're closed. - No.
-我現在就要他的骨灰  -不好意思
- I need his remains now. - I'm sorry.
我明天一早就走 我不能拋下他
I'm flying first thing. And I can't leave without him!
是... 大衛·梅爾羅斯
It's... David Melrose.
求你了
Please?
可以要個紙袋嗎
Could I possibly trouble you for a paper bag?
現在  瑪麗安
Now, Marianne.
我有500克可卡因  0.2克海洛因
I have half a gram of coke, a fifth of heroin,
一份安眠酮  一份黑美人
one Quaalude, one Black Beauty.
幾句暖場對白
A few lines to get the conversation flowing,
一份讓瑪麗安心情愉悅的安眠酮
a Quaalude for Marianne to get her in the mood.
也許傷心也是種理由
Perhaps pity is the way,
讓人在失落的時候 還能在飛機上小憩
in which case use it for the comedown, sleep on the plane.
上帝保佑 你沒事的
My God, you're good.
然後你回到家 感謝協和號飛機
Then you're home, thank Christ for Concorde.
強尼會等著你...
Johnny will be waiting and...
見機行事吧
Well, let's see.
你好 我是帕特裏克 瑪麗安的朋友
Hello, I'm Patrick, Marianne's friend.
南希 南希·班克斯 我們見過
Nancy, Nancy Banks. We have met.
是的
Yes, of course. Oh!
抱歉 我剛有點走神了 這是...
Sorry, bit distracted. It's just...
沒事 瑪麗安說了 是你父親嗎
Yes, Marianne told us. Is that him?
我讓康蘇拉加一個人的飯
I'll tell Consuela there'll be one more for dinner!
瑪麗安
Marianne!
她可想見你了
She is dying to see you!
傑瑞 你還記得帕特裏克吧 黛比小可愛的男朋友
Jerry, you remember Patrick, lovely Debbie's boyfriend.
我在你們的洗手間暈倒了
I turned blue in your bathroom.
-我們只好把門卸了  -是我
- We had to take the door off! - Yes!
-進來  -正是本人
- Come in, come in! - 'Tis I.
瑪麗安說他很了不起
Marianne says he was a remarkable man.
你們應該聽聽我的事跡
Hm! You should have heard the remarks.
你們的關係不太好是嗎 帕特裏克
Was it a difficult relationship, Patrick?
是的 南希 挺不容易的
Yes, Nancy. Yes, it was.
-悲劇什麼時候開始的  -1906年7月9日
- When did the trouble start? - 9th June, 1906.
他出生那天
The day he was born.
那個年代當爸爸跟現在不同
Well, fatherhood was very different in those days.
是的 也許他只是不知道怎麼表達愛
Yes, perhaps he just didn't know how to express his love?
殘忍是愛的對立面
Cruelty is the opposite of love,
不是愛的另一種表達
not some inarticulate expression of it.
我同意
That sounds about right to me.
噢 瑪麗安...
Oh, Marianne...
但我從不用擔心這個
Although, that's not something I've ever had to worry about.
-你好 帕特裏克  -你好
- Hi, Patrick. - Hello.
對於你父親的離開 我很遺憾
I'm so, so sorry for your loss.
你就是答案 我的救星 你知道嗎
You're the answer. You're the one to save me, can't you tell?
我想死在這裏
I want to be buried here.
如果能擁有你 我願意一輩子不沾毒品
If I could have you, I'd give up drugs forever.
我的天
Goodness!
或者至少找個有魅力的人一起吸毒
Or at least have someone attractive to take them with.
我們共進晚餐好嗎 答應我吧
Can we go out to dinner? Please say yes!
-你喜歡這裏嗎  -當然 我喜歡亞美尼亞菜
- Does this look alright to you? - Absolutely. I love Armenian.
你穿著外套不熱嗎
Are you gonna be hot in your coat?
你看著不舒服的話...
Oh. If it makes you feel uncomfortable, then...
-有點  -好的 馬上脫
- A little. - Well, off it comes.
也許我應該把眼罩也摘下來...
Perhaps I should take my eye-patch off too...
還是戴著吧 請上兩杯馬提尼
I'll leave it on. Two martinis, please.
-一杯就行  我不喝酒  -不喝嗎
- One. I don't drink. - Don't you?
情況不妙 非常非常不妙
Bad sign. Very, very bad.
喝酒會讓視線模糊  反應遲鈍
I find it blurs the edges and dulls the senses.
你的意思是
Your point being?
我完全同意
I absolutely agree.
我也不常喝 只有傷心的時候才...
I don't usually either but, you know... grief.
找點話題 別忘了步驟
Say something, remember how this is done,
除了撒謊 取笑和蔑視都行
Something other than lies or ridicule or contempt.
黛比向你問好
Debbie sends her love.
-說這個幹嘛 傻逼  -黛比太好了
- Not that, you fucking idiot! -  Sweet Debbie.
-她還好嗎  -她是個很好的女孩
- How is she? - Oh, she's a great girl.
非常非常有同情心
Very, very supportive.
換個話題
Change the subject.
她說你在學習法律
She tells me you're studying law.
是的 在哥倫比亞大學
That's right! At Columbia.
很難 但我喜歡
It's really tough, but I love it.
我也想過學法律
I once thought about studying law.
想像自己像"十二怒漢"那樣 唇槍舌劍
Imagined myself in Twelve Angry Men, terrifically articulate,
懲惡揚善...
righting wrongs...
你會成為一名出色的律師
You'd have been a wonderful lawyer.
-謝謝誇獎  -你應該試試
- Thank you. - You absolutely should do it!
-為什麼不呢  -因為努力
- Why don't you? - 'Cause hard work
-和野心都沒有用  -天啊
- and ambition are vulgar. - Oh, my God,
你不相信這句話吧
you don't believe that, do you?
我嗎 不 沒有 是我父親說的
Me? No, no, no, no, That's what he said.
你受過良好教育 而且...
Well, you have an education and...
謝謝 我意思是...
Thank you. I mean...
而且 你跟你父親不一樣
And besides, you're not your father.
你說的太對了
You are absolutely right.
你知道嗎 我備受鼓舞
Do you know what? I feel inspired!
下飛機我就準備這事
I'm gonna do something about it the minute I get off the plane.
脫胎換骨 聽到了嗎 爸爸 我要當律師了
A new man! Do you hear that, Dad? I'm gonna be a lawyer!
帕特裏克 我有點擔心那個盒子
Patrick, I'm concerned about the box.
不用管它 就當做隨身行李就好
Don't be, I think it counts as hand luggage.
不不不... 你能把它放地上嗎
No, no, no, I mean... Could you put it on the floor?
好
Yes!
隨服務員們踢去吧 終於報仇了
Let the waiters kick him about. Revenge at last!
為什麼他死了就能逃避一切
Why should he get away with it, just because he's dead?
逃避什麼
Get away with what?
不好意思 我離開一下
I'm sorry. Will you forgive me?
我以為你喜歡亞美尼亞菜
I thought you liked Armenian food?
馬提尼酒挺好喝的
The martinis are excellent.
"爸爸媽媽毀了你的生活
"They fuck you up, your mum and dad.
也許不是有意 但事實如此" [語出詩人拉金 "這就是詩"]
They may not mean to, but they do."
誰說他們不是故意的
Who says they don't mean to?
你跟你爸說過自己的感受嗎
Tell me, did you ever tell your dad how you felt about him?
他活著的時候 沒有
Not while he was alive.
-也許這樣最好  -為什麼
- Probably for the best. - Why?
我想知道 你會說什麼
I mean, what would you have said to him?
我... 我會告訴他...
I... I would have said...
我會跟他說...
I would have told him...
"沒人能那樣對待任何人"
"Nobody should do that to anybody else."
-謝謝  -對不起
- Thank you so much. - Oh, sorry.
我很認真在回答
I took the question seriously.
對不起 你剛說什麼
Oh, no, I'm sorry, you were saying?
我說...
Just that...
算了
Never mind.
帕特裏克 我... 得回家了
Patrick, I... I should be getting back.
不不不 瑪麗安...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Marianne...
你我之間是有感覺的 對嗎
We've always had a connection, haven't we?
不是我一廂情願
I mean, I'm not just imagining it.
不 我一直很喜歡你和黛比
Well, no, I've always been very fond of you and Debbie.
你想來點安眠酮嗎
I don't suppose you want to do a Quaalude, do you?
抱歉我狀態不好
I'm sorry for being a bit screwy.
沒關係 情緒激動期
No. It's an emotional time.
出租車 晚安 帕特裏克
Taxi! Good night, Patrick.
晚... 好的
Good... Yes.
晚安 晚安
Good night. Good night!
你知道嗎 有時候我覺得自己要是遇到了對的人
You know, sometimes I think if I was to meet the right woman,
聰明 敢於挑戰我的女孩
someone intelligent, who wasn't afraid to challenge me,
我也許真能回歸正常的生活
I might actually be able to get my life back in order.
得了吧 別犯傻了
Please, stop. You are making a fool of yourself.
不 求你了 別走
No, please, don't go.
我真的需要陪伴 不然我不知道自己能做出什麼來
I really need the company or I don't know what I'll do.
滾開 自甘墮落的垃圾
Get the fuck off of me! Self-indulgent little shit!
你到底什麼毛病
What is wrong with you?
我是個笨蛋 對不起 可求你了 別走
I'm an idiot, I'm sorry, but, look, please don't go!
今晚我不想一個人待著 我不能
Look. I don't wanna be on my own tonight, I can't.
沒別的人 就陪我坐坐吧
And there isn't anyone else. Just sit with me.
別丟下我孤單一人
Don't leave me alone!
可你不孤單啊
But you're not alone.
開車
Let's go.
她說得對 我不孤單
She's right. You're not alone.
永遠不會
And you never will be.
死亡與毀滅
Death and destruction.
恥辱與暴力
Shame and violence.
難以控制的恥辱與暴力
Ungovernable shame and violence.
給我滾開
Just fuck off!
靠 靠
Fuck! Fuck!
操
Fuck!
我要把你衝下馬桶
I'm gonna flush you down the loo,
衝到下水道裏跟鱷魚和屎一起
send you to the sewers with the alligators and the shit.
怎麼可能
How?
這破窗戶有什麼用
What's the point of a fucking window
跳樓都不行
if you can't jump out of it?
我想死
I want to die.
我想去死
你又不是沒辦法
Well, it's not as if you don't have the means.
先打麻藥 對吧 醫生
Anesthetic first, surely, Doctor?
不 帕特裏克
No, Patrick.
先開刀 再打麻藥
Scalpel first, anesthetic afterwards.
噓 你安全了 沒人能發現你在這兒
Ssssh! You're safe. Nobody can find you here.
可沒有人發現我怎麼辦呢
But what if nobody finds me here?
老天爺 好一個破爛垃圾堆
Good God, what an appalling dump.
看我淪落到什麼地步了嗎
You see what I'm reduced to?
你媽媽肯定很高興
Your mother will be delighted.
可以想到你跟她匯報時 她洋洋得意的樣子
I can see her gloating, when you report back.
你會向她匯報嗎
Do you report back?
現在...
Now...
你睡左邊還是右邊
Left or right?
無所謂
Don't mind.
我已經筋疲力盡了
I'm a very tired man.
過來跟我聊聊天 帕特裏克
Come and talk to me, Patrick.
帕特裏克 過來跟你親愛的老爹聊聊天
Patrick. Come and talk to your dear old dad.
拜託...
Please...
快 快 快 快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
讓我們速戰速決
Let's just go ahead and finish it.
媽媽
Mummy?
親愛的
my darling.
真抱歉叫醒你
I'm so sorry to wake you.
現在幾點了
What time is it?
還早
It's very early.
我們要出發了嗎
Are we going now?
我真的想走
I do want to go.
非常想
Very much.
"太陽升起
"And the sun shone, having no alternative,
一切如常"
on the nothing new."
生活不只是袋屎 還是袋漏了的屎
Life's not just a bag of shit, but a leaky one.
你無法避免碰到它
You can't help being touched by it.
你沒發現嗎
Don't you find?
先生 我相信這是人類共識
I believe, sir, that's the common consensus.
"鮮血將匯成河流 惡人將溺死河中
"There will be rivers of blood and the wicked shall be drowned.
高地也難以倖免
Nor shall the high places be spared.
橋樑將被沖毀
And the bridges shall be swept away.
人類將會宣告
And men shall say that the end of the world
末日的降臨" [原著中行李員稱此言出自"聖經"]
cometh upon them."
他們說的很有道理
And they shall have a point.
非常有道理
They shall have a very good point.
誰能說我不懂享樂呢
Well, no-one can say I don't know how to have fun.
您的車在等您了
Your limo is waiting.
希望您此行愉快
And we hope you enjoyed your stay with us!
可不只是愉快
Enjoyed isn't the word.
我愛死這兒了
I loved it!
先生 梅爾羅斯先生 先生
Sir! Mr. Melrose, sir!
-您差點忘了這個  -真的嗎
- You nearly forgot this! - Or did I?
先生
Sir?
我是說... 不用打電話到維也納了
What I mean is... no need to call Vienna!
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
-那個 血流成河是吧... -先生
- So, rivers of blood...  - Sir
沒什麼
Never mind.
算了
算了吧
Never mind.
飛往倫敦希思羅機場的BA002次航班最後廣播
Final call for Flight BA002 to London Heathrow.
請乘坐BA002次航班的旅客
Would all passengers for Flight BA002
現在到登機口等候
please make your way to the boarding gate now.
拜託 接電話啊
come on, come on.
強尼 強尼
Johnny, Johnny.
-能聽見嗎  -能 你怎麼樣
- Can you hear me?  - That's it, how are you?
還行吧 昨天晚上我想自殺來著
Fine. I tried to kill myself last night.
天啊 你從哪兒打來的
My God. Where are you calling from?
-地獄  -媽呀 你還好嗎
- The bottom. - Christ, are you alright?
帕特裏克 你什麼時候落地 我去接你
Patrick? Tell me when you land. I'll come and meet you.
聽著 我時間不多了 能聽見嗎
Look, I haven't got long. Can you hear me?
能
Yes.
我決定了 我要掌控我的生活
I've decided, I'm gonna take control of my life.
我要戒毒
I'm gonna get clean.
喂 強尼 你能聽見嗎
Hello, Johnny. Can you hear me?
能 太好了 可...
Yes, I can. That's wonderful, but...
-你這次是認真的嗎  -當然了
- Are you sure this time? - Of course.
你們怎麼老大驚小怪的
People always make such a fuss about these things.
那你打算怎麼辦
So what do you want to do?
帕特裏克
Patrick?
帕特裏克 那你準備幹嘛
Patrick, what are you going to do instead?
你在聽嗎
Are you there?